Guide to the John Hutton, College Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
"College correspondence: Letters from candidates for Parliamt. 1779"
1778-1783
OSBORN C108
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.8
(1 volume)
Autograph MS and contemporary MS copies. Collection of letters addressed to Hutton by various correspondents (including copies of a few of Hutton's own letters); many concern Parliamentary Candidates for Cambridge University, and nearly all of Cambridge interest, discussing College and University matters.
Hutton, John, 1739-1806
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c108. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Elections -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Intellectual life -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1760-1820; Correspondence; Barnes, Francis, 1744-1838; Hutton, John, 1739-1806; Mansfield, James, Sir, 1733-1821; Pearce, William, 1744-1820; Pitt, William, 1759-1806; Townshend, John, Hon., 1757-1833; Great Britain. Parliament; University of Cambridge
- Osborn c108
  - BACKHOUSE, JAMES, 1720-1790
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 Dec 29 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Cambridge
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      108/23
  - BARNES, FRANCIS, 1744-1838
    - 3 ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779 (Box 1)
      King's College, Cambridge
      10 p.; various sizes
      Letters concern University and
      personal matters.
      108/39-41
  - BARNES, FRANCIS, 1744-1838
    - 13 ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779-81 Nov 15 (Box 1)
      19 p.; various sizes
      108/43-55
  - BARNES, FRANCIS, 1744-1838
    - 5 ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1782-83 (Box 1)
      1782 Jan 1 - 1783 Jan 31
      9 p.; various sizes
      108/57-62
  - BARNES, JOSEPH
    - ALS to his son, Francis Barnes (1744-1838), 1778 Jan 15 (Box 1)
      [Lancaster]
      4 p.; 17 x 20 cm.
      Statement of expenses for his
      schooling at Eton College.
      108/38
  - CARUS, WILLIAM WILSON, 1765-1851
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1782 Mar 21 (Box 1)
      On the author's entering the
      University.
      108/63
  - CARUS, WILLIAM WILSON, 1765-1851
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1782 Nov 23 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Reports on his progress at the
      108/64
  - CLARENDON, THOMAS VILLIERS, EARL OF, 1709-1786
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 Sep 26 (Box 1)
      n.p.
      2 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Regrets that no places are
      available.
      108/2
  - CLARENDON, THOMAS VILLIERS, EARL OF, 1709-1786
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779 Jun 3 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Includes a Post-Script added by
      Richard Beadon, bp. of Bath
      and Wells
      (1737-1824).
      108/3
  - CLARENDON, THOMAS VILLIERS, EARL OF, 1753-1824
    - 5 ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779-80 (Box 1)
      1779 Aug - 1780 Sep 25, The Grove
      7 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      Electioneering letters.
      108/4-8
  - CROFTES, RICHARD, CA. 1740-1783
    - 1 ALS and 4 LS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779-80 (Box 1)
      1779 Jul 7 - 1780 Dec 12
      Jermyn Street
      9 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      108/12-17
  - FLETCHER, GEORGE
    - ALS to Francis Barnes (1744-1838), 1779 Oct 17 (Box 1)
      Lancaster
      2 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Explanation of why Joseph Barnes
      (father of Francis) gave a bond to
      John Nightingale.
      108/42
  - GRAFTON, GEORGE HENRY FITZROY, DUKE OF, 1760-1844
    - LS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 Mar 3 (Box 1)
      Includes Post-Script by Richard
      Watson, bp. of Llandaff (1737-1826).
      108/18
  - GRAFTON, GEORGE HENRY FITZROY, DUKE OF, 1760-1844
    - LS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 Sep 7 (Box 1)
      Hull
      108/19
  - HUTTON, JOHN, 1740?-1806
    - Letter (copy) to Thomas Villiers, 1st earl of Clarendon (1709-1786), 1780 Sep 23 (Box 1)
      [Burton]
      1 p.; 23 x 15 cm.
      Seeks a place for his uncle,
      William Hutton.
      108/1
  - HUTTON, JOHN, 1740?-1806
    - ALS (copy) to Richard Croftes (ca. 1740-1783), 1780 Nov 14 (Box 1)
      Burton
      2 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      Seeks a place for Arthur Kirby.
      108/16
  - MANSFIELD, SIR JAMES, 1733-1821
    - LS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1770 Aug 20 (Box 1)
      Temple
      Solicits votes.
      108/20
  - MUNCASTER, JOHN PENNINGTON, BARON, 1737-1813
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 Dec 30 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      108/22
  - NIGHTINGALE, MARGARET (BARNES)
    - LS to Francis Barnes (1744-1838), 1781 Oct 26 (Box 1)
      Bolton
      2 p.; 20 x 17 cm.
      Asks Francis Barnes, her brother,
      advice about her son's education.
      108/56
  - PEARCE, WILLIAM, 1744-1820
    - 12 ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779-82 (Box 1)
      1779 Mar 10 - 1782 Dec 17
      28 p.; various sizes
      Letters concern university and
      personal matters; in letter no.
      29, there is a detailed account
      of a political meeting in the
      Senate House Yard, at which John
      Wilkes (1727-1797) was the
      principal speaker.
      108/26-37
  - PITT, WILLIAM, 1759-1806
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779 Jul 24 (Box 1)
      108/21
  - TOWNSHEND, LORD JOHN, 1757-1833
    - 1 ALS and 2 LS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1779-80 (Box 1)
      1779 Jul 7 - 1780 Sep 2
      4 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      108/9-11
  - WATSON, RICHARD, BP. OF LLANDAFF, 1737-1816
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1782 Mar 20 (Box 1)
      [Cambridge]
      1 p.; 11 x 19 cm.
      108/24
  - WILTON, THOMAS EGERTON, EARL OF, 1749-1814
    - ALS to John Hutton (1740?-1806), 1780 May 24 (Box 1)
      Windsor Castle
      108/25